자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
Her name is penny garden.
피해자 이름은 페니 가든이야
Age 65.
65세이고
Retired cocktail waitress.
은퇴한 칵테일 바 웨이트리스지
Been living here since the rat pack days.
랫 팩(50~60년대 유행한 미국의
전설적인 그룹) 시절부터 여기 살았고
She may have served them drinks.
그 사람들에게 서빙을
했을지도 모르겠군요
Well,they must have tipped well
흠, 그랬다면 팁을
후하게 받았을 거야
because 20 years ago
this was a nice neighborhood.
20년 전에는 괜찮은 동네였으니 말이야
Anyway, a guy next door
heard a racket,called 911.
어쨌건, 옆집 남자가 소음을 듣고
911에 전화했어
Down the hallway,
there's a spare bedroom.
복도 끝에도 침실이
하나 더 있어
The bed's unmade.
침대는 정리되지 않았어
So if the vic had a houseguest,
그러니까 만약 피해자에게
손님이 있었다면
they're nowhere to be found,
so I'm going to dig around.
여기에는 없는 게 확실해
내가 주변을 좀 조사해 볼게
Unfortunately,
these windows aren't tempered.
불행히도, 유리창이
강화유리가 아니야
Very dangerous if broken.
깨지면 매우 위험하죠
And she went through face first.
그리고 피해자는
머리부터 튀어나갔어
The door's right here--
I doubt she missed it.
문이 바로 여기 있는데
그걸 못 보진 않았을 것 같아요
Maybe she had some help.
누군가 그렇게 만들었을 거예요
God.
아악
those coupons on the
floor on top of the glass
바닥의 쿠폰들은
유리 위에 떨어져 있어요
suggests they were scattered
after the window broke.
유리가 깨진 후에
흩어졌단 얘기네요
Maybe they went through the
room after they killed her.
범인들은 피해자를 살해한 후에
방을 가로질러 갔을 거야
There's nothing particularly valuable here.
여기에는 특별히 값나가는 것이
없어보이는데요
There used to be.
이젠 없는 거겠지
싱크편집
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글번역
정영선(jysun70@dreamwiz.com)
번역수정
박수희(wren79@nate.com)
한글수정
안은정(actwo@nate.com)
월리암 피터슨(길 그리섬 役)
CSI 레벨3(반장), 전문분야: 곤충학
마그 헬겐버거(캐서린 윌로우스 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 혈흔 분석
게리 도단(워릭 브라운 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 음향/시각 자료분석
조지 이즈(닉 스톡스 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 머리카락, 섬유질 분석
조자 폭스(새라 사이들 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 물질성분 분석
에릭 스즈맨다(그렉 샌더스 役)
CSI 레벨1, 전문분야: DNA분석
로버트 데이비드 홀(알 로빈스 役)
검시관, 전문분야: 법의학
루이스 롬바드(소피아 커티스 役)
라스베가스 시 경찰청 형사
폴 길포일(짐 브래스 役)
라스베가스 시 경찰청 경감
CSI: Crime Scene Investigation
7x07 Post Moterm
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2006/11/09
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
My name is Pete Athens.
신사숙녀 여러분
제 이름은 피트 아텐스로입니다
I am the coroner of clark county.
I want to thank you all for being here.
클락 군의 검시관이죠
여기 와 주신 모든 분들께 감사드립니다
Coroner inquests go back to medieval times
during the reign of richard I in england.
검시의 시작은 중세시대 영국 리처드 왕
1세의 치세로 거슬러 올라갑니다
In fact,"coroner" comes from the word "crown."
사실 '검시관'이란 단어는
'왕관'에서 파생된 것으로
A public inquest was one of the crown's checks
and balances on the powers of the sheriff.
배심원의 심리는 왕권을 견제하고
행정관과 균형을 잡기 위한 것이었습니다
And today,a thousand years later,
그리고 수백 년 후 오늘날에도
it serves the same purpose in our county--
우리나라에서 같은 기능을
담당하고 있습니다
checks and balances on the sheriff
and for those who work for him.
즉, 경찰청장과 그 기관에 종사하는 사람들을
견제하고 균형을 유지하는 것입니다
The honorable Clayton Trueblood
will be our hearing master.
존경하는 클레이톤 트루블러드 씨께서
이 심리를 이끌어가실 겁니다
He's not a judge,
but he's going to be more like a um...
저분은 여기서 판사가 아니라
오히려...
a traffic cop because an inquest isn't a trial.
교통경찰 같은 역할을 하실 겁니다
이 심리는 재판이 아니니까요
We're going to examin
the death of demetrius james.
우리는 드미트리어스 제임스의
사망에 대해 조사할 겁니다
The assistant district attorney Valerie
Nichols will present the facts in the case,
발레리 니콜 검사가 이 사건의
사실들을 제시하고
introduce the witnesses
and ask them questions.
증인들을 소환하고
그분들께 질문을 할 겁니다
Any member of the jury
may also ask questions,
배심원 여러분도 누구나
질문을 하실 수 있습니다
either orally or in writing.
구두나 서면으로요
I understand that there are family
members of the deceased present.
사망자의 가족들이
참관하고 있으신데요
I'm very sorry for your loss,
가족을 잃으신 일은
정말 유감입니다
and I want you to know that
as what the state calls "interested parties,"
그리고 진술서에 있는 대로
여러분은 '이해 당사자'들이므로
you may ask questions, too.
역시 질문을 하실 수 있음을
알려드립니다
When all the facts have been presented,
모든 사실들이 제시되면
the jury will then rule the death
in question as either justifiable,
배심단은 이번 사망 사건이
정당방위나 면죄가능인지
excusable or criminal.
아니면 유죄인지를
판결할 것입니다
Cut's pretty deep. Let's try and
keep her head on while we move her.
꽤 깊게 베였어요. 옮기는 동안
머리가 붙어 있도록 노력해 보자고요
On three
셋에 하죠
One,two,three.
하나, 둘, 셋
Hi. / Hi.
나 왔어 / 오셨어요
Grissom said you could use some help.
반장님이 자길 도와주라고 하시든데
What haven't you done?
아직 안 한 데 있어?
The rest of the house.
여기를 뺀 집안 전체요
Hope I die before I get old.
늙기 전에 죽었으면 좋겠네
Man,I was just lampin' in the crib
with my boys when all of a sudden, psssh
전 친구들과 저기서 쉬고 있었거든요
그런데 갑자기, 푸쉬~
I thought someone was
breaking in next door.
누군가 옆집에 침입한 거라고 생각했죠
Took a look over the fence,
old Penny was breaking out.
울타리 너머로 살펴보니
페니 할머니가 튀어나와 있었어요
Did you hear anything?
Any voices, yelling, screaming?
무슨 소리 들은 거 있습니까?
목소리나, 고함, 비명 같은 거?
I don't even think mrs.
Penny could scream.
페니 할머니가 비명을 지를 수
있을 거라곤 생각지 않는데요
She had, like, a real low,raspy voice.
할머니 목소리는 정말 낮고 선정적이든요
Yeah. Well, you think that's sexy?
당신은 그게 섹시하다고 생각하신 건가요?
Is that the way you roll? Huh?
그런 게 당신을 흥분시키나요?
All right,I'll take that for a "no."
좋아요, 아니라고 말씀하신 걸로
알아듣죠
You see anybody leave the house?
저 집을 나온 사람이 있었습니까?
No,sir.Not last night.
아뇨, 어젯밤엔 없었어요
Who's she got staying with her?
피해자는 누구와 같이 살았죠?
Don't know his name, but I seen
him always going in and out of there.
이름은 모르겠어요. 하지만
그 사람은 늘 들락날락하더군요
- Describe him.
- White dude.Skinny.
- 인상착의를 말해봐요
- 백인 남자고, 말랐어요
Always wears jeans and white tees.
늘 청바지에 흰 티셔츠를 입었죠
Man.
저런
I liked that old lady.
전 그 할머니를 좋아했어요
She made some good victuals and
always had an extra stogie if I was out
훌륭한 음식도 만들어 주시고
밖에 나와 있으면 담배도 주셨어요
This is my card.
이건 제 명함입니다
If you see that white skinny guy
give me a call, will you? / Yeah.
그 마른 백인 남자를 보면
전화해 주겠소? / 예
All right? / Yeah.
알겠죠? / 예
You talk to that guy in that house?
저 집주인과 얘기해봤어?
Been there twice.
Still nobody home.
두 번이나 가봤는데
아직 아무도 없어요
Put someone on his
doorstep until he shows.
주인이 나타날 때까지
문 앞에 누군가 세워놔
He's got security cameras.
I want the video.
저 집에는 보안카메라가 있다고
그 테이프가 필요해
The first attack that night
occurred just after midnight,
그날 밤 첫 폭행 사건은
자정 직후에 발생했습니다
in the employee parking structure
at the golden sapphire hotel.
골든 사파리 호텔의
직원 주차장에서요
A group of youths ranging from
teen to early 20s attacked Vasco Ruiz,
10대에서 20대 초반의 젊은이로 구성된
폭도들이 배스코 루이즈를 폭행했습니다
a hotel dishwasher on his way to his car.
루이즈 씨는 호텔의 접시닦이로
차로 가던 중이었죠
He was apparently selected at random.
루이즈는 그저 무작위로
선택된 것 같습니다
Mr.Ruiz was found dead at the scene.
루이즈 씨는 현장에서
사망한 채 발견되었습니다
And what was the mob's next move?
폭도들은 다음에
어디로 이동했습니까?
Approximately 30 minutes after the first attack,
첫 폭행 후
약 30분쯤 뒤에
not far away,at the holiday motel,
별로 멀지 않은 홀리데이 모텔에서
they attacked their next victim,
Jessica Hershbaum.
다음 희생자인 제시카 허쉬바움을 공격했습니다
- Now,miss hershbaum survived
- She's alive.
- 허쉬바움 양은 생존했죠?
- 살아 있습니다
But she has physical
and emotional scars from the attack
그러나 폭행에 의해
정신적, 육체적 상처를 입었고
that she may never recover from.
평생 회복하지 못할 수도 있습니다
So when mr. Sanders was
coming to your crime scene,
그럼 샌더스 씨는
범죄 현장에 도착했을 때
would he have known about
these first two swarming attacks?
먼저 있었던 두 차례의 집단
폭행에 대해 알고 있었습니까?
Absolutely.
분명히 알고 있었습니다
CSI was still processing
those crime scenes,
CSI는 그때까지도
그 현장을 조사중이었거든요
and then I heard on my radio
about another attack--the third that night--
그리고 저는 또 다른 폭행, 그날 밤의
세 번째 폭행에 대한 무선 연락을 받았습니다
and that a CSI was one of the victims.
피해자 중 한 명이
CSI 직원이라는 것도요
Is this the location of
the third swarming attack?
이곳이 세 번째 집단 폭행 장소입니까?
Yes.I drove over there immediately.
예. 전 즉시 그곳으로 갔습니다
And what did you find?
현장은 어떠했죠?
Three men,all seriously injured.
심각한 부상을 입은
세 명의 남자가 있었는데
Stanley Tanner was unconscious,
as was demetrius james.
스탠리 태너는 의식 불명이었고
드미트리어스 제임스와
and CSI sanders
CSI 대원 샌더스도 마찬가지였습니다
The mob had pulled CSI sanders
from his vehicle and beaten him.
폭도들은 CSI 대원 샌더스를
차에서 끌어내서 폭행했습니다
But it was his intervention
that saved Stanley Tanner's life.
하지만 스탠리 태너가 목숨을 건진 건
바로 샌더스가 끼어들었기 때문이었습니다
While I appreciate your
participation in the process here,
심리에 참여해 주셔서
감사하기는 하지만
I don't find this question relevant.
이 질문은 관련이 없다고 생각합니다
Excuse me, your honor.
The question's quite relevant.
죄송하지만 재판장님
그 질문은 관련이 있습니다
Are we just going through the motions here,
지금 여기서 우리는 심리를 하는
시늉만 하는 건 아닌가요?
so it looks like someone actually
asked whether or not it's okay
마치 흑인 애들을 차로 치는 것이
옳은지 그른지 판단하는 소송이
to run over black kids in the street?
실제로 제기된 것처럼 말이죠
- Do you have a question, sir?
- Yeah.
- 질문이 있으신 겁니까?
- 예
Are you also going to be
censoring verbal questions?
재판장께서는 구두 질문도
검열하실 예정이신가요?
Relevance is at my discretion here.
관련 여부는 제가 판단합니다
Now please, take your seat.
이제 자리에 앉으시죠
Multiple lacerations on face,
neck shoulders--
안면과 목, 어깨에
다수의 열상이 있어
if it weren't for the couple dozen
glass fragments I tweezed out,
내가 직접 핀셋으로 유리 조각을
잔뜩 집어내지 않았다면
I'd say somebody went to town
on her with a straight razor.
누군가 면도칼로
난도질했다고 생각했을 거야
C.O.D. is exsanguination due to sharp
force injury to the jugular carotid complex
사인은 예리한 물건에 의한
경동맥 손상으로 일어난 과다출혈이야
but she was already on her way out.
하지만 피해자는 어차피
죽을 운명이었더군
Cannonballs of tumors on her lungs.
폐에 탄피 만한 종양들이 가득이야
Man...her cancer had cancer.
저런... 암세포도 암에 걸렸네요
I guess she liked smoking
more than living,huh?
목숨보다 담배를 더
좋아했나 보군요, 그렇죠?
Or else she wanted to die
with a cigarette in her mouth.
아니면, 입에 담배를 물고
죽기를 바랐거나 말이야
You know,Catherine found antidepressants
,laxatives,acid-reflux meds in her house,
캐서린이 그 집에서 항우울제와
변비약, 위장약을 발견했어요
but I don't think she found anything for pain.
하지만 진통제 종류는
발견되지 않았는데요
I guarantee you,this lady was in pain.
분명히 이 할머니에겐
통증이 있었어
She must have been taking something for it.
통증을 없애려고
뭔가를 복용했을 거야
Maybe the killer took it with him.
살인범이 가져갔는지도 몰라요
Well,there's a big market for that stuff now.
요샌 그런 물건들이 꽤 잘 나가지
I'll get her medical records.
피해자의 진료기록을 살펴 볼게
Did you find something?
뭔가 발견한 게 있어요?
Bloody glass.
피묻은 유리조각이야
The killer on his way out?
살인범이 이곳으로 나간 걸까요?
You can't keep me out of there!
This is where I live,man!
절 막을 수는 없어요!
여긴 내 집이라고요!
Sorry,son.This is a crime scene.
You don't want to be in there.
미안하지만 여긴 범죄 현장입니다
당신은 들어갈 수 없어요
Look,I just want to see my auntie Penny.
Where is she?
전 단지 페니 이모를 만나려는 것
뿐이에요. 이모는 어디 계세요?
- Calm...calm down.
- I don't want to calm down!
- 진정해요... 진정하라고
- 진정하고 싶지 않아요!
Do you live here?
여기 사시나요?
Yeah,that's what I was just telling this guy.
What's going on?
예, 이분들에게 그 애기를 하고
있었어요. 무슨 일인가요?
- What's your name?
- Henry. Henry Briney.
- 이름이 뭐죠 ?
- 헨리요. 헨리 브라일리
Henry,I'm going to need you to come down
to the police station, give us a statement.
헨리 씨, 경찰서에 가서
진술서를 써주셔야겠어요
For what?
뭐 때문에요?
sorry to tell you,but your aunt is dead.
이런 말 하게 돼서 유감이지만
당신 이모가 돌아가셨어요
Mr.Tanner,can you tell us what injuries
you sustained as a result of the attack?
테너 씨, 그 폭행으로 어떤 부상을
입게 되셨는지 말씀해 주시겠습니까?
Cuts,some of them pretty bad,
mostly on my face.
주로 얼굴에 심한 열상을 입었는데
어떤 것은 아주 심했습니다
Broke left arm,
왼팔이 부러지고
crushed windpipe,
기관지가 뭉개지고
one eye socket cracked,
한쪽 눈구멍에는 금이 가고
broke right ankle.
오른쪽 발목이 부러졌어요
And I got this headache they
tell me might be permanent.
그리고 그 사건 후 생긴 두통은
완치가 안 될 수도 있다고 하더군요
Would it be correct to say that
while you were being attacked,
테너 씨가 폭행당하는 동안
you felt like your life was in danger?
생명에 위협을 느꼈다고
해도 되겠습니까?
- Hell,yeah.
- I have a question.
- 물론이죠
- 질문 있습니다
Go ahead.
질문하시죠
Did you actually see
demetrius james attacking you?
드미트리어스 제임스가 당신을
공격하는 것을 직접 보셨습니까?
Oh,I couldn't tell who was who.
오, 누가 누군지는 모르겠습니다
I mean,hell,my hands were on my face.
전 손으로 얼굴을
보호하고 있었으니까요
I was just trying to stay alive.
그저 살아남으려고
노력하고 있었죠
If mr.Sanders hadn't shown up just then,
I'd have been like that first guy--dead.
만약 샌더스 씨가 그때 나타나지 않았다면
저는 첫 피해자처럼 죽었을 거예요
There was a large laceration
where Demetrius James'
드미트리어스 제임스의 머리에는
땅에 부딪히면서 생긴
head hit the ground when he fell
커다란 열상이 있었습니다
Underlying that wound was a
fracture of the occipital bone,
그 상처 밑에는
두개골의 기저를 횡단하는
which crosses at the base of the skull.
후두골 골절이 있었습니다
The motion of the impact
caused the brain to collide
충격으로 뇌가 두개골 내부의
with the bony protrusions inside the skull
돌기된 뼈에 충돌했습니다
resulting in what we call
contra-coup contusions.
그 결과, 전문용어로
'반동에 의한 상해'가 발생했습니다
There was also prominent cerebral edema--
또한 현저한 대뇌 부종
또는 팽창이 발견되었고
or swelling-- as well as
hemorrhages of the brain stem
뇌간의 급격한 손실도 있었습니다
So your official cause of death was...?
그래서 공식적인 사인은 뭡니까?
Blunt force trauma to the head
following a motor vehicle collision
교통사고에 의한 두부 외상입니다
So this was a death at the hands of another?
그럼 다른 사람에 의한
사망이란 말이죠?
Yes.
예
And what do you call that kind of death?
이런 종류의 사망을
당신들은 뭐라고 부릅니까?
A homicide.
타살입니다
So where did you go last night?
그래서 어젯밤에는
어디에 갔었습니까?
- Movies.
- Oh, a ticket stuB. That's good.
- 영화관에요
- 오, 극장표라. 그거 좋군요
Who'd you go with?
You went by yourself?
누구랑 같이 갔죠?
혼자 갔었소?
Who else would I go with?
도대체 누구랑 같이
간다는 말이에요?
I don't know.A friend?
나야 모르죠
친구?
No.I don't have friends.
전 친구가 없어요
Okay,so the movie ended.
You're all by yourself,then what?
좋아요. 그래서 영화가 끝났고
당신은 내내 혼자였고, 그리고 나서는요?
I sat in the keno lounge all night,
전 케노(도박의 일종) 도박장에
밤새 앉아 있었어요
hit the grocery store,
and then came home to cops.
식료품을 사서
집에 와보니 경찰이 있었죠
Why are you staying at your aunt Penny's?
왜 당신은 이모와 함께 살고 있죠?
Because my parents threw me out.
부모님이 절 쫓아냈으니까요
Why would they do that?
부모님은 왜 그러셨죠?
Because they don't like me.
절 싫어하시니까요
Let me see your arms.
팔 좀 봅시다
Are you booting that good "doodgie"?
마약을 하고 있습니까?
You ever use intravenous drugs?
마약을 정맥주사로
놓은 적이 있어요?
Not anymore, but I did for a while.
이젠 안 해요
전엔 한동안 했었죠
You know,your aunt Penny had some
scrips for some pain medication--
당신 이모 페니는
진통제를 처방받았는데
oxycontin, fentanyl, methadone.
옥시콘틴, 펜타널, 메타돈이요
When we searched her house,
we didn't find any.
우리가 집을 뒤졌을 땐
하나도 발견하지 못했거든요
Did you take them?
혹시 당신이 가져갔소?
No,I didn't take them.
아뇨, 제가 가져가지 않았어요
She must have taken them.
I don't touch them.
이모가 치웠겠죠
전 손도 대지 않았다구요
I just got out of rehab.
전 이제 막 재활치료를 마쳤어요
Haven't touched a pill,
line or needlein six months
6개월 동안 알약도, 분말도
주사도 안 했어요
My parents threw me out,
우리 부모님은 절 내쳤지만
and she took me in.
I would not screw her over.
페니 이모는 절 받아줬어요
전 이모를 등치는 일은 안해요
We're going to need to take your
clothes and your shoes
당신 옷하고 신발을 벗어줘야겠소
Any luck?
나온 거 있어?
No.
아뇨
No blood on the nephew's shoes or clothes.
조카의 옷과 신발에선
혈액이 검출되지 않았어요
Drug panel on his urine came back negative.
He's clean.
소변검사에서도 아무것도 안 나왔어
조카는 결백해
What about auntie Penny?
페니쪽은 어때요?
No pain meds in her system either.
그쪽 혈액에서도
진통제는 검출되지 않았어
We've got a lot of serious drugs
that are unaccounted for.
자료에 올라 있지 않은
심각한 약들도 많잖아요
These glass fragments are from the mob
breaking out the windows of CSI sanders' denali
이 유리조각은 폭도들이 CSI 대원
샌더스의 차창을 깰 때 나온 것입니다
That's how they dragged him out.
그렇게 해서 창으로 샌더스 씨를 끌어냈죠
This is a clump of his hair,
이건 샌더스 씨의 머리카락 뭉치입니다
torn from his scalp.
두피에서 쥐어뜯긴 거죠
And that's the rock Demetrius
James used as a weapon.
그리고 저것은 드미트리어스 제임스가
무기로 사용한 돌입니다
According to who?
누가 그러던가요?
This is the first we've even heard
that Demetrius James had a weapon
드미트리어스 제임스가 무기를
사용했다는 얘기는 처음 듣는데요
In his report,
Mr.Sanders testified to that fact.
샌더스 씨의 진술서에 있는 내용입니다
The rock was found at the scene.
저 돌은 현장에서 발견되었습니다
How do we know the
cops didn't plant it there?
경찰이 가져다 놓은
건지도 모르잖아요?
- Sir,I've warned you.
- I'd like to answer that question.
- 경고합니다
- 그 질문에 대답하고 싶습니다
Usually,when someone plants a weapon,
whoever did it puts it right beside the body--
누가 흉기를 가져다 놓을 때는
시체 바로 옆에다 두는 것이 일반적입니다
in this case, the rock was found
near the front tire of the denali.
이 경우에는, 돌이 발견된 장소는
샌더스 씨 차의 앞타이어 옆입니다
Skid marks suggest it was
dropped upon impact.
타이어 자국으로 볼 때, 차에
부딪힌 충격으로 떨어뜨린 겁니다
A rock against two tons of steel.
돌과 2톤짜리 강철 덩어리의
대결이었군요
No. More like one man against
an extremely violent, out of control mob
아뇨. 굉장히 폭력적이고 광분한
폭도들 대 한 남자의 대결이었죠
What's department policy in a situation like that?
경찰 지침에 따르면 그런 경우
어떻게 해야 하죠?
It has always been department policy
not to harm innocent civilians.
결백한 시민을 다치게 해서는
안 됩니다
You call for backup,
you try to be a good witness,
지원을 요청하고, 증언을 잘할 수
있도록 현장을 주시해야 합니다
and you stay out of the way.
그리고 직접 뛰어들지는 말아야 하죠
So what makes it okay to
start running over people?
그럼 사람들을 향해서 달려든 일을
정당화할 수 있는 근거는요?
Well,when those people are wearing masks,
running around beating people up.
그 사람들이 복면을 쓰고 돌아다니며
사람을 패고 있을 때는 예외죠
Man,D.J.Was going to a costume party.
이봐요, 형은 가장 파티에 간 거였어요
One victim was dead.
Another was seriously injured.
피해자 한 명은 사망했습니다
다른 한 명은 심하게 다쳤고요
Another fatality imminent.
또 한 명이 죽음을
목전에 두고 있었어요
I'd say the use of deadly force in this case was
consistent with department policy,absolutely
이 사건에선 사력을 다하는 것이
경찰 지침과도 부합한다고 확신합니다
Demetrius James was going to
finish off the victim with the rock
드미트리어스 제임스는 저 돌로
피해자를 끝장내려고 했어요
You're a liar!My brother wasn't a killer!
거짓말쟁이!
우리 형은 살인자가 아니야!
-Excuse me.
-Demetrius was going to college
- 여보세요
- 드미트리는 대학에 갈 거였어요
-Mrs. James.
-He had a 3.6 gpa.
- 제임스 부인
- 그 애의 평점은 3.6이었다고요
We are all very sorryfor your loss,
but you are not a witness here.
아드님께 일어난 일은 정말 유감입니다
그러나 부인께서는 증인이 아니에요
- You didn't know him!
- DJ had a future!
- 당신들은 내 아들을 모르잖아요!
- 형에겐 미래가 있었어요
- I knew him! We knew him!
전 알아요!
우리는 그 애들 잘 안다고요!
Judge,can we have some order here?
판사님, 장내를 정리해 주시겠습니까?
You didn't run over a mob,
you ran over one boy!
당신은 폭도에게 달려든 게 아니야
한 소년에게 달려든 거라고!
My boy!
내 아들에게!
judge?
판사님?
Mrs.James' comments give context
to the events of the night in question
제임스 부인의 진술은 그날 밤 사건의
정황을 이해하는 데 도움이 될 겁니다
I'd like to hear what she has to say.
부인의 얘기를 들어보고 싶군요
Why is trueblood letting her do this?
왜 재판장은 저걸 허락하는 거죠?
It's probably good for his campaign.
자신의 선거유세에 도움이
될 테니까 그러겠죠
He's running for assembly.
주의원에 출마했거든요
Now you tell me.
일찍 말해주시지 그랬어요
Got your page.
호출받고 왔어
Surveillance footage from the
neighborhood watch guy across the street
이웃집 감시 카메라는 맞은편 집에
사는 남자를 찍고 있었어
Yeah,he was paranoid,but lazy.
예, 그 사람 편집증은 있지만
게으른가 봐요
Had four security cameras on his house,
그 집에는 감시 카메라가 4대 있는데
three of them were cardboard boxes.
그 중 3대는 가짜예요
Homemade security is the worst.
집에서 만든 보안장치는 최악이죠
Okay,so the nephew comes in and out
of the house a couple times during the day
자, 보세요, 저 조카는 하루에
몇 번씩 집을 들락날락하고 있어요
It's a whole different story next door.
이웃집은 상황이 전혀 달라요
Okay,this guy
이 남자 좀 보세요
comes out of the house and
meets with a different car
집에서 나와서는 매번
다른 차와 접촉하고 있어요
at least three times and hour
한 시간에 최소 세 번씩은요
He's slinging drugs.
저 남자 약을 팔고 있어
FIND IN YOUR HOUSE.
당신 집에서 발견했소
The white one is carisoprodol.
하얀 것은 캐러소프로돌이더군요
It's a muscle relaxant.
근육 이완제지
Yeah,I strained my pecs bench pressing.
예, 역기 들다가
가슴 근육이 뒤틀렸거든요
Oh,yeah.
And the blue one is prevalis.
오, 그래요
파란 것은 프리발리스요
You look a little young to need that.
이게 필요할 나이는
아직 아니실 텐데
Well,I've had my share of women.
음, 여자들한테 좀 나눠줬어요
Mr. Johnson's gotten
bored over the years,so?
제 거시기가 몇 년간 좀
심심해해서 말이죠
Well,he's going to get really
bored in prison.You hope
아마 감옥에서는 훨씬 더
심심해질 거요
What,you gonna bust me for selling prevalis?
프리발리스 좀 팔았다고
저를 체포하시려고요?
Well,you think a guy in my job doesn't know
글쎄, 나 같은 형사들은
클럽과 길거리에서
what goes on in the clubs and in the street?
일이 어떻게 돌아가는지
모를 거라 생각하시나 본데
You ever hear of a Las Vegas cocktail.
라스베가스 칵테일이라고 들어봤소?
I don't drink.
저는 술 안 마셔요
It's a combination of carisoprodol,
그건 캐러소프로돌과 프리발리스
prevalis and very strong
painkiller called fentanyl.
그리고 초강력 진통제인
펜타닐을 섞은 거요
Problem is,fentanyl's hard to get.
I mean,doctors don't just give it away,
문제는, 펜타닐은 아주 구하기 어렵다는
거지. 의사들이 처방을 잘 안 해주거든
you got to be in really serious
pain to get it, like dying of cancer.
그걸 처방받으려면, 정말 심한 통증이
있어야 해요. 말기 암 같은 거 말이오
On the street it's called "perc-a-pop".
길거리에서는 펄크-어-팝이라 불리지
Now,Penny Garden was
prescribed 40 a month.
자, 페니 가든은 한 달에
그걸 40개씩 처방받았소
Problem is,
we couldn't find any in her house.
문제는, 집에서 그 약이
하나도 안 나왔다는 거지
So what, you think I stole them?
그래서, 제가 훔쳤다는 건가요?
Yeah,I do.
맞아, 난 그렇다고 보는데
Where are the pops, old lady?
팝은 어딨어요, 할멈?
Get out of my house.
이 집에서 나가
- Where are they?
- I'll call the police.
- 약은 어딨어요?
- 경찰에 전화할 거야
No you won't.
그렇겐 안될걸
Never.
Never, never, never.
절대, 절대, 절대 아니에요
Look,I told you, I liked the lady.
보세요, 전 그분을
좋아했다고 했잖아요
She made me dinner.
She lent me smokes, man.
저한테 저녁도 만들어 주고
담배도 빌려줬어요
You liked her 'cause she
had what you needed.
자네가 필요한 것을 가지고 있으니까
좋아했던 거 아니오?
No,man.No way.
Hey,I need a lawyer in here.
아니에요, 말도 안 돼요
변호사를 불러주세요
So we have a drug dealer
and a former drug user,
용의자로 마약상과
전직 중독자가 있는데
both of which would have
motive to steal penny's drugs.
둘 다 페니의 약을
훔칠 동기가 있어요
Well,there wasn't any trace
of fentanyl in the nephew's system
글쎄, 조카 혈액에서는 펜타닐이
전혀 검출되지 않았잖아
He's broke,he's unemployed,
조카는 빈털터리에 무직이니까
maybe he's stealing them penny
so he can sell them to the neighbor.
주변에 팔려고 훔쳤을지도 모르죠
If that's the case, it's motive for both.
그 경우라면 두 명 모두에게 적용되지
Excuse me.
실례합니다
Hi, henry.
What are you doing here?
안녕하세요, 헨리 씨
여기서 뭐 하는 거예요?
Um...I just found this on my porch--
음... 저 이걸 저희 집
현관에서 발견했는데요
I opened it and thought I should
bring it down to you guys.
열어봤더니, 여기
가져와야 할 것 같아서요
It's... pretty creepy.
그게... 꽤 괴기스러워요
If one was horrifying...
하나로도 공포스러웠는데
...what is two?
두 개가 되면 뭐가 되는 거죠...?
Possible serial killer.
연쇄살인범일 가능성이 되지
I'd say that it takes the nephew
and the neighbor off the hook.
이렇게 되면, 두 사람 다
용의선상에서 제외되는데요
I doubt either one of them
could afford a mini-contractor, anyway
둘 다 미니어처를 살 수 있을 만한
여유는 없어 보여요
A bloody doll.
피묻은 인형이네요
Similar to the one in the other miniature.
지난번 미니어처에
있던 것과 비슷해요
Look at the blood on the doll's forehead.
인형 이마에 있는 피를 봐
Same pattern on both.
모양이 둘 다 비슷해요
Could be two different
views of the same subject.
같은 인형을 다른 각도에서
찍은 걸 거야
Maybe it's a signature.
서명 같은 것일지도 몰라요
Yeah,but we have no context.
그래, 하지만 우리에겐
맥락이 없잖아
It could mean or represent just about anything.
이게 뭘 의미하거나 상징하는지
알 수가 없어
Okay...again,
좋아요... 다시 생각해 보죠
the miniature suggests that
the killer had an intimate familiarity
이 미니어처는 살인범이
피해자들의 집, 습관 등을
with victim,home and habits.
아주 잘 알고 있었다는 걸
보여주고 있어요
So what do they have in common?
그럼 피해자들의 공통점은 뭘까요?
Izzy delancy,50-year-old white male,
washed-up rock star.
이지 델란시는 50세 백인 남성
한물간 록 스타였고
Penny garden,cancer-stricken retiree.
페니 가든은 암 걸린 퇴직자였지
Different friends,different family,
different social circles.
친구도, 가족도
속한 사회 집단도 달라요
Why wasn't this one left
at the crime scene like that one?
왜 이번 것은 지난번 것처럼
현장에 놓여 있지 않았을까?
Marla and Aaron James
are not sworn witnesses.
말라와 에론 제임스는
정식 증인이 아닙니다
If they were,they couldn't
be in the courtroom during testimony
정식 증인이었다면 증언하는 동안
법정에 있을 수 없었을 겁니다
and that would effectively take away their rights
as interested parties to question witnesses.
그럼 이해 당사자로서 증인들에게
질문할 권리를 박탈당했을 거고요
So please try to remember
that their remarks are not evidence
그러니 이들의 진술은 증거가
될 수 없다는 것을 명심해 주십시오
Go ahead.
시작하시죠
My sons didn't grow up with a father.
내 아들들은 아버지 없이 자랐어요
Barely had a mother...
엄마도 없는 거나 마찬가지였고요...
on account of me working all the time.
전 하루종일 일했으니까요
They got into trouble.
애들은 말썽을 일으켰죠
Mostly 'cause of where we live.
대부분은 주변환경 때문이었어요
Aaron here,he got into
a whole lot of trouble.
여기 있는 애론은
문제를 많이 일으켰어요
And I did my time,too.
그래서 저는 감옥에도 갔어요
I did my time, but that wasn't D.J.
전 감옥에도 갔었다고요
하지만 형은 달랐어요
He was helping me turn my life around.
형은 제 인생을 바꿀 수 있도록
도와주고 있었어요
Coached me on my ged.
제 검정고시 공부를 도와줬고요
Made me feel like there was
a chance for me, you know.
제게도 기회가 있다는 걸
느끼게 해줬어요
Man,you have no idea what you
killed when you killed my brother.
이봐, 당신은 자신이 누굴
죽인 건지 결코 모를 거야
Everyone was moved by
the compelling testimony...
다들 피해자 드미트리어스 제임스 모친의
of the victim's mother...
of Demitrius James
호소력 있는 증언에 감동받았습니다
today, in the courthouse,...
instead it was the mother,
오늘 이 법정에서...
대신에 모친이
that had the courtroom
asking did her son behave...
법정에서 아들의
행동에 대한 질문에...
hey. / Nichols was right.
This isn't a trial,it's a circus.
그렉 / 니콜이 맞았어요
이건 재판이 아니라 서커스예요
Yeah,I heard.
Starring the mother.
그래, 들었어
엄마의 연기가 뛰어났다면서
I feel like I should say something.
제가 무슨 말이라도 해야
할 것 같은 생각이 들었어요
Like what?
어떤 말?
- I don't know.
- Sorry?
- 모르겠어요
- 미안하다고?
You going to apologize to the mother of a guy
한 사람을 때려죽이고
who beat one man to death
and was trying to do the same to you?
너한테도 똑같이 하려던 사람의
엄마에게 사과를 하려고?
That's as good as saying you're guilty
그건 유죄를 인정하고
and setting yourself up
for one hell of a civil suit besides.
자신을 민사재판에 회부하겠단 얘기야
You did nothing wrong.
넌 잘못한 게 하나도 없어
I just want to be able to sleep again.
전 다시 잠을 잘 수
있길 바랄 뿐이에요
We put ourselves in harm's
way every single day
우리는 날마다 위험에 직면하고 있고
and sometimes, we pay one
hell of a price for surviving it
때로는 살아남기 위해
큰 대가를 치르기도 해
Other people will never understand that.
다른 사람들은 그걸 결코
이해할 수 없을 거야
No way D.J. Was a violent person.
형은 결코 폭력적인 사람이 아니었어요
My son is not a killer.
제 아들은 살인자가 아니에요
He was trying to stop that killing.
그 애는 살인을 막으려고 한 거예요
Hey. / Hey.
어이 / 응
How'd it go in there?
법정에선 어떻게 되고 있어?
I don't know.
나도 모르겠어
Really? / Yeah.
정말? / 응
You know,I know it was a hardcore
situation that Greg ran up on
있잖아, 그렉이 지금 상당히
곤란한 상황이란 건 알아
but you think it ever
would have occurred to him
만약에 반대로 그렉이
거기서 그냥 도망쳐버렸더라면
to just put it in reverse
and get the hell out of there?
그래도 일이 이렇게 되었을까?
Well,that's not the question.
글쎄, 그게 문제가 아니라고 보는데
What a jury wants to know is did Greg do
배심원이 알고 싶은 건 다른
분별 있는 사람들도 그 상황에서
what any reasonable person would
have done under the circumstances.
그렉과 같은 행동을 했겠느냐는 거야
I know greg must have
been scared as hell,man.
그렉이 얼마나 공포에 떨었을까
What can we do to help him?
우리가 뭔가 도와줄 수 있을까?
We'll put the jury behind the wheel of the car.
배심원들을 운전석에 앉혀보자
All right,the denali's black box
reports only five seconds before impact
좋아, 그렉이 몰던 차의 블랙박스 기록을
보면 충돌까지 5초밖에 안 걸렸어
Now, Greg was idling
with his foot on the brake.
그렉은 브레이크를 밟고 있었고
And then he accelerated
for no more than two seconds
다음엔 가속한 건 2초도 안 돼
Yeah,according to the
acceleration skid marks,
그래, 가속에 따른
타이어 자국을 보면
the front end went from there to there
차 앞부분은 저기에서
저기까지 이동했고
with D.J. Coming at him.
드미트리어스는 그렉을
향해 오고 있었지
Want to give it a go?
한번 해볼까?
- Take it for a spin?
- Yeah.
- 한번 질주해 볼래?
- 좋아
- you ready?
- Ready.
- 준비됐어?
- 그래
Go.
가
stop.
정지
With this kid running at him the whole time,
그 애가 달려들고
있었다는 점을 감안하면
there's no way greg
could have avoided hitting him.
그렉이 사고를 피하는 건
불가능했어
You think a jury will see it that way?
배심원들도 그렇게 생각해줄까?
how tough you feel when
you're not in your big suv,huh?
커다란 차 안에 있지 않아도
네놈이 강하다고 생각해? 응?
I asked you a question, killer.
너한테 묻고 있잖아, 살인자야
Excuse me.
실례합니다
In the cause now pending before this court
현재 심리중인 소송사건에 대해
Do you swear to tell the truth,
당신은 이 법정에서
the whole truth and nothing but the truth?
진실만을 말할 것을 맹세합니까?
- I do.
- Be seated.
- 맹세합니다
- 앉으셔도 좋습니다
All right,let's take a look at the official
transcript of your call for backup.
좋아요, 당신이 했던 지원 요청의
공식기록 사본을 봅시다
01:54 and 21 seconds,
dispatch control answers.
01시 54분 21초에
지령실이 응답했어요
Would you please read your response.
당신의 답변을 읽어주시겠습니까?
"Control,control,this is CSI Sanders.
I need some help."
"지령실, 지령실, CSI 대원
샌더스입니다 . 도움이 필요해요"
You took a couple of seconds
to look at the street signs.
다음에 몇 초간
도로 표지판을 살펴봤어요
There's a few more exchanges
and then dispatch tells you:
서로 몇 마디 주고받은 후
지령실은 당신에게 말했습니다
"Closest unit has a five minute ETA."
"가장 가까운 팀이
5분 거리에 있다"
Five minutes.
5분입니다
Control continues--
"rolling code 3. Are they armed?"
지령실은 말을 계속했죠--
"순찰 코드 3, 상대는 무장했습니까?"
Please read your response.
당신의 대답을 읽어주세요
I don't know, I don't know.
Ma'am,please,listen:
잘 모르겠어요, 모르겠습니다
제 말 좀 잘 들어주세요
- They gotta get here quicker than this.
- Copy that.
- 그보다 빨리 와야 해요
- 알았습니다
What'd you do?
다음엔 어떻게 하셨나요?
I thought I'd try to break up the mob.
폭도들을 흩어지게
해야 한다고 생각했어요
I turned into the alley,
골목 안으로 들어가서
hit the horn,yelled,anything.
경적을 울리고, 소리치고
다 했어요
Did that stop the beating?
그래서 폭행이 멈추었나요?
Not entirely.
전혀요
One guy decided not to run away.
한 명은 도망가는 대신
Instead,he turned around,picked up a rock...
돌아서서는 돌을 집어들었어요
and moved like he was going
to finish off the victim.
피해자를 끝장내려는
것처럼 보였죠
But he turned and started coming at me with it.
그런데 돌아서서는 돌을 든 채
제게 달려오기 시작했어요
Oh,come on,that's just his word,man.
이봐요, 그건 저 사람
주장일 뿐이에요
His word against my brother's word!
형 말하고는 완전 반대라고요!
Mr.James. / You know,
we can't get his side, now can we?
제임스 씨 / 우리가 저 사람
말을 믿을 수 없다는 건 알잖아요
All right.Your honor?
좋습니다, 재판장님?
The man has a right to speak,Ms. Nichols.
그 사람은 말할 권리가
있습니다, 니콜 씨
Sit down. Come on.
앉아라
진정하고
At this point,
그 순간에
- did you fear for your life?
- Yes.
당신은 생명의 위협을
느꼈습니까? / 예
- Did you have a weapon,a gun?
무기를 소지하고 계셨나요?
총이라든가 / 아니오
What were you thinking
무슨 생각이 드셨죠?
when D.J. Left Stanley
Tanner's unconscious body
드미트리어스 제임스가 의식을 잃은
스탠리 테너 씨의 곁을 떠나
and ran at you with that rock?
돌을 든 채 당신에게
달려들었을 때요
I thought that he could
make me his next target.
그 사람이 저를 다음 목표로
삼을 거라 생각했어요
I thought he wanted to kill me.
저를 죽일 거란 생각이 들었고요
No matter what,
I knew that I had to incapacitate him
무슨 일이 있어도 그 사람을
저지해야 한다는 걸 알았어요
Now it's taken us several minutes
to go through the events of that night
이제까지 그날 밤의
사건을 돌아보았습니다
And I'm sure that you've all formed
some kind of opinion about what happened
그리고 여러분께서는 그날 밤에 생긴
일에 대해 의견이 있으실 겁니다
But,right now,let's put ourselves
in Mr. Sanders' position.
그러나, 이제 직접
샌더스 씨의 입장에 서 보시죠
Let's see how much time Greg
had to save a man's life.
한 생명을 구하기 위해 샌더스 씨에게
과연 얼마만큼의 시간이 있었는지 보시죠
Seconds.
몇 초
Mere seconds.
단지 몇 초뿐이었습니다
What would you have done?
여러분 같으면 어떻게 하셨을까요?
Mr. Sanders,
샌더스 씨
was it your intention to kill Demitrius James?
드미트리어스 제임스를
죽일 의도가 있었나요?
No.
아뇨
I wish he hadn't come at me.
저한테 달려들지 않았다면
I wish that he had just run away.
그냥 달아나 버렸다면
좋았을 겁니다
Mr. Sanders...
샌더스 씨
aren't you leaving something out?
뭔가 빠뜨린 건 없습니까?
I don't think so.
없는 것 같은데요
You testified at a criminal trial
earlier that day,didn't you?
당신은 그날 형사재판에서
증언을 했었지요?
Yes. / A.D.A. Ulrich
예 / 얼리크 검사는
당신 증언에
must've been pleased with your testimony.
꽤 만족했었나 보군요
She took you to dinner at the tillerman.
틸라만에서 저녁을 대접했으니까요
I'm looking at a copy of
her credit card receipt.
제가 지금 보고있는 것은 그 검사의
신용카드 사용 내역입니다
How was the sea bass?
농어 요리는 어땠습니까?
And the bottle of pinot grigio
santa margherita 2005, how was that?
그리고 피농 그리지오 산타 마그리타 한 병
그건 좋았나요?
Your honor...
재판장님...
I... wasn't on shift,and I only had...
전 근무 중이 아니었습니다
그리고 단지...
Mr. Sanders,
I'm sure the jury's wondering,
샌더스 씨, 배심원들도
궁금해하실 겁니다
if you hadn't been drinking
before going to work,
만약 당신이 일하러 가기 전에
술을 마시지 않았다면
would Demitrius James still be alive?
드미트리어스 제임스는 아직
살아있지 않았을까요?
Alcohol wasn't...a factor.
알코올은 문제가 아니었습니다...
A.D.A. Ulrich insisted on ordering the wine.
얼리크 검사님이
와인을 주문하자고 우기셨어요
I drank half a glass.
About six ounces.
전 반 잔을 마셨을 뿐입니다
약 180cc요
At my weight, 150, that would
give me a blood-alcohol content of .02%
제가 약 68kg이니까, 혈중
알콜농도는 약 0.02%가 됩니다
Even without food,
식사를 안 했어도 말이에요
the alcohol burn-off rate
would be .015% per hour...
알콜의 분해속도는
시간당 0.015%입니다
meaning that there was no alcohol
in my bloodstream after 90 minutes
90분이면 제 혈액에서 알콜은
없어진다는 뜻입니다
well before I reported for my shift and about...
그건 제가 근무 신고를
하기 훨씬 전, 그리고
seven hours before the incident.
약 7시간 후
사고를 당하기 전입니다
This is where we found your aunt's fentanyl
so we know that you didn't take it.
여기서 당신 이모의 펜타닐이 발견됐고 그래서
당신이 가져간 게 아니라는 게 밝혀졌어요
Which means you've gone from a suspect...
당신은 용의자에서
to a witness.
증인이 되었다는 뜻이죠
Now it's up to you
to help us find the real killer.
자, 이제 진짜 살인범을 잡도록 우릴
도와줄 것인지는 당신에게 달렸습니다
If you really cared about penny,
진정으로 그분을 좋아했다면
you'll tell us the truth about everything.
모든 것을 사실대로
얘기해줘야 할 거요
-So this is off the record?
-Yeah.
- 이건 비공식적인 거죠?
- 그래요
So I ain't going to jail?
그럼 전 감옥에 안 가는 거죠?
Yeah,what do you want to know?
좋아요, 그럼 뭘 알고 싶으세요?
Who was Penny hiding her drugs from?
이모님은 누구에게서 약을
감추려고 한 걸까요?
I don't know.
Maybe it was me.
모르겠어요
저일지도 몰라요
Although I never would've taken them.
전 절대 훔치지 않았을 거지만요
Or maybe you should ask the guy next-door.
아니면, 옆집 남자에게
물어보셔야 할 거예요
No,man,I'd never take those things from her.
이봐, 아니야, 난 결코
할머니한테서 약을 뺏지 않았다고
I buy 'em,50 bucks a pop.
제가 그 약을 하나당
50달러에 샀어요
did you know your aunt was selling her drugs?
이모님이 자신의 약을 팔고
있었단 걸 알고 있었나요?
Yeah,I had an idea.
예, 알고 있었어요
I figured it was how she
was supporting her habit.
그렇게 해서 이모가 취미를 계속
즐길 수 있는 거라고 생각했죠
Which one?
어떤 취미요?
I guess I should've said "habits."
취미들이라고 하는 게 맞겠네요
she loved her liqueur,
and she loved her cigarettes,
이모는 음주와 흡연을 즐겼어요
but what she really loved was video poker.
하지만 제일 좋아했던 건
비디오 포커였죠
She liked the sound the coins made
when she hit a jackpot.
이모는 패를 맞췄을 때 동전이
떨어지는 소리를 좋아했어요
She offered me a couple of bucks a week
to keep the house clean,and...
집 청소하는 대가로 저에게
일주일에 몇 달러씩 주셨는데
And she paid me in nickels and quarters.
25센트와 5센트짜리 동전으로 주셨죠
Can you think...
그 약이 거기에 있다는 걸
of anyone else that might have known
that those drugs were there?
아는 사람이 또 있지는 않았을까요?
No.
아뇨
I lived with her for a couple of months,and...
그 집에서 이모랑
몇 달간 같이 살았는데
and she never had anyone over but me.
저 말고는 찾아오는 사람이
아무도 없었어요
I know that look.
그 표정을 지으시는군요
You just figured something out.
방금 뭔가 알아내신 거예요
This is much better than
dead rock star kitchen.
이건 죽은 록 스타의
부엌보다 훨씬 낫네요
The whole al fresco thing?
야외무대 같은데요?
Come on,share.
그러지 말고
저도 좀 알자고요
Please?
제발요
Look carefully at the back of the doll
인형 등을 자세히 봐
and at the pillow on the chair.
그리고 의자 위의 쿠션하고
There appears to be remnants of glue on both.
양쪽에 모두 접착제의
흔적이 남아 있어
So the doll was originally glued
to the back of the chair.
그럼 인형을 원래 의자에
붙였었단 얘기네요
I think the killer expected the victim
to die in this chair.
내 생각에 살인자는 피해자가
의자에서 죽을 거라고 예상했던 것 같아
Well,if that's the case,
then how did the killer expect to...kill her?
그렇다면 살인자는 어떻게
피해자를 죽이려고 했던 걸까요?
I understand the jury has reached a verdict?
배심원께서는 평결을 내리셨습니까?
We have,your honor.
그렇습니다, 재판장님
We,the jury in this inquest,
find the death of demitrius james excusable
이 심리의 배심원은 드미트리어스 제임스의
사망이 면죄가능함을 평결합니다
well,thank you,ladies
and gentlemen, judge trueblood.
여러분, 그리고 재판장님 감사합니다
This inquest is concluded.
이 심리를 종결합니다
"Excusa..." no.
면죄라니 말도 안 돼요
See,"excusable" is a lawful
act with no intention to kill.
면죄가능이란 살해 의도가 없었던
적법행위를 말하는 거예요
"Justifiable" means that the
action was the only alternative.
정당방위란 선택의 여지가
없었던 행위를 말하고요
That's what they should have found.
이건 당연히 정당방위였어야 해요
It's okay.
괜찮아요
I think they may have it right.
그 사람들이 옳은 건지도 몰라요
Look,look,I got nothing
against mr.Sanders
이봐요, 전 샌더스 씨에게
개인적인 원한은 없지만
personally but all these inquests ever
really seem to do is protect the cops.
이 심리는 전부 경찰을
보호하기 위한 것으로 보여요
As I have emphasized during my campaign,
public deserves the truth
제 선거유세에서 강조한 대로
대중은 진실을 알 권리가 있습니다
...about any death at the
hands of law enforcement.
법 집행 과정에서 발생한
모든 죽음에 대해서 말입니다
No, it's not over.
We don't get the justice...
아뇨, 아직 끝나지 않았어요
우리는 결코 정의가...
Mr. Sanders, mr. Sanders,
do you think the verdict was fair?
샌더스 씨, 샌더스 씨
평결이 공정했다고 생각하시나요?
Was your killing demitrius james excusable?
당신이 드미트리어스 제임스를
죽인 사건이 면죄가능한 겁니까?
This kid saved my damn life.
He is a hero, a genuine hero.
이 친구는 내 생명을 구했어요
이 친구는 영웅이라고요, 진정한 영웅이요
penny garden was poisoned with nicotine.
페니 가든은 니코틴 중독으로 죽었어
Well,that's not exactly a surprise--
the woman smoked liked a chimney.
글쎄, 그건 별로 놀랍지 않네요
굴뚝처럼 담배를 피워댄 사람이니까요
She didn't smoke it.
She drank it.
흡입한 것이 아니라 마셨어
Liquid nicotine.
액체 니코틴을 말이야
Truman Capote used it as a
murder weapon in his story,
트루만 캐포티는 그의 소설에서
액체 니코틴을 살인 도구로 사용했지
"hand-carved coffins,"
"수제 관들"이란 책이야
and our killer put it
in aunt penny's liqueur bottle.
이 살인범은 그걸
페니 할머니의 술병에 넣었어
A cigarette introduces approximately
one milligram of nicotine into the body
담배 한 개피는 체내에
약 1밀리그램의 니코틴을 남겨
The liqueur contained over 60.
술에는 60밀리그램 이상이 있었어
A dose that massive can
induce severe convulsions...
그만한 양이면 심한 경련을
일으킬 수 있으니
...and evidently,mess up
a meticulously crafted murder.
세밀하게 계획된 살인을
망쳐버린 것도 당연하지
That's why the miniature
wasn't at the crime scene.
그래서 미니어처가
현장에 있지 않았던 거야
The killer was compelled to fix it,
살인범은 그걸 고쳐야만 했던 거지
so that it would match
what actually happened.
실제 범죄 현장과
일치하도록 말이야
Liquid nicotine is in a lot of
smoking cessation products
액체 니코틴은 많은 금연상품에
사용되고 있어요
Yeah.
Commonly available to just about anyone.
그래
누구나 쉽게 구할 수 있지
Any luck with the vic's calls?
피해자 통화 기록에서는
뭐 나온 거 없어?
I data-mined the home phone numbers
of Izzy Delancy and Penny Garden.
이지 델란시와 페니 가든의 집
전화통화 목록을 조사해봤는데요
They actually had ten numbers in common.
일치하는 번호가 10개 나왔어요
Information,
정보 조회
couple of mail-order catalogs,
power company, moviefone.
통신 판매 카탈로그 몇 군데, 전력회사랑
영화 상영시간 알려주는 전화하고
There's one other number
which turned out to be
그리고 번호가 하나 더 있었는데
조사해 보니
an untraceable disposable cell phone--
추적 안 되는 일회용 휴대전화
번호로 밝혀졌어요
suggests someone
who doesn't want to be found.
신분을 밝히고 싶지 않은
사람이 있다는 얘기죠
Hey, boss, unless you need me
for something, I'm gonna take off.
반장님, 제가 필요한 일이 없으시다면
그만 퇴근하고 싶은데요
Yeah.Take off that suit,too.
그래
그 양복도 벗어버려
And greg...
그리고 그렉...
you did a good job.
자넨 잘했어
I'm glad you think so.
그렇게 생각해주셔서
다행이에요
you've been served.
법원 출두 명령서입니다
what is it, archie?
뭐야, 아치?
Oh, hey, gris.
보세요, 반장님
I was just looking at footage
from the next-door neighbor's
그냥 이웃집 감시카메라 필름을
돌려보고 있었거든요
the night the package was delivered.
그 미니어처가 배달된
그날 밤 거요
never underestimate the neighborhood watch.
이웃집의 감시를 무시하면
안 되겠더라고요
I don't see a delivery truck.
배달 트럭은 안 보이는데
fortunately for us,
this was a personal delivery...
우리한테는 행운이군
범인이 직접 배달하다니
right to our front door.
바로 현관 앞까지 말이야
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)